Guide to the Cormac McCarthy Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Child of God, 1970-1971, undated
  - Drafts, 1970-1971, undated
    - Photocopy draft with significant pencil editorial notes addressed to "Mac." 161 pages (164 leaves), undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Proofs, undated
    - Setting copy; photocopy with page composition order. 161 pages (169 leaves), undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Photocopy of stamped setting copy. 161 pages (169 leaves, plus manila folder with holograph title, "Child of God"), undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Page proofs with layout markings. 197 pages (196 leaves plus cardboard), undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of page proofs, lightly corrected. "Dead matter" in red pencil on front page. 197 pages (102 leaves), undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of pages proofs, uncorrected, stamped "Master Set, 2nd Pass." 197 pages (103 leaves), undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Page proofs with minor annotations. 197 pages (104 leaves in 7 sections), undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Page proofs marked "Erskine" and stamped, "Hand folded samples from Bloomsburg Craftsmen." 197 pages (104 leaves in 8 sections), undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
- The Gardener's Son, 1976, undated
  Correspondence, research, drafts, and production material relating to McCarthy's screenplay, Gardner's Son. It originally aired on the Visions series on PBS, January 6, 1977.
  - Correspondence, 1976, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - McCarthy to Dick Pearce, TL. 2 pages, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      "A hurried note. I think the dock scene should go after McEvoy passes James Gregg's office on page twenty five…"
    - McCarthy to Dick Pearce. Photocopy of TLS, 1 page, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      "I hope this will be of some use to you but I dont guarantee anything. Concerning specific actors, I think Royal Dano would be a good man to play the doctor…" suggests Keenan Wynne for Patrick McEvoy, also John Savage. Recommends John Cullum for role of James Gregg and James Earl Jones for Whipper.
    - Dick Pearce to McCarthy, June 3, no year, ALS, 2 pages, undated
      Sending tape of a 67 year old Graniteville mill hand singing traditional mill songs as well as other research materials [no tape included].
    - Dick [Pearce] to McCarthy. ALS, 2 pages (1 leaf), undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Call Sheet and Directions to Worthville, April 17, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Research, undated
    - "William Gregg, of South Carolina," from Gallery of Industry and Enterprise, pages 348-352. Photostat, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - The Advent of William Gregg and the Graniteville Co., edited by Thomas P. Martin, reprinted from August, 1945 The Journal of Southern History, Vol. 11, No. 3, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "William Gregg." Photocopy, 5 pages, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Honorable William Gregg The Founder of Graniteville." June 5, 1879. Transcription from the Edgefield Advertiser, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Horses Don't Eat Moon Pies" by Pat Conroy in Faces of South Carolina, pages 47-56. Photocopy, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Manufacturers in South Carolina" by J.H. Taylor in De Bow's Review Vol. 8, No. 1, January 1850, pages 24-29. Photocopy, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Manufacturers in South Carolina and the South" in De Bow's Review Vol. 11, No. 2, August 1851, p. 123-140. Photocopy, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Honorable William J. Whipper." Photocopy, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Trial. State of South Carolina. vs. Benjamin Booth, Marion Booth, Sampson Booth, Davis Kissick and John Carpenter. Indictment for Murder. Photocopy, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Untitled photograph print: deceased infant, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of South Carolina State Archives materials, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of several newspaper articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Holograph research notes, 9 pages (6 leaves), undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Drafts, undated
    - Typescript with pencil corrections. 113 pages, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy of typescript in box 18, folder 4, incomplete, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Production Material, 1976, undated
    - Shooting script in yellow binder marked "Cormac McCarthy." Contains a few pencil notes. 140 pages, circa 1976 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Characters in order of their appearance," 7 pages; Directions to Worthville, 1 page; Call sheets, April 1976. 4 leaves (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Suttree, 1977-1978, undated
  Correspondence, notes, drafts, fragments, and proofs relating to McCarthy's 1979 novel, Suttree.
  - Correspondence, 1977-1978, undated
    - Albert Erskine to McCarthy. TLS, 4 pages, May 27-29, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Recommends a more compact mss before submitting it for copy editing and production. Focuses on a few episodes that he feels need improvement.
    - McCarthy to Bert [Bertha Krantz, copy editor]. TLS, 1 page, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
      "Here tis. I made a note or two in the margins, addressed to you, nothing of earthshaking importance…" Describes changes and the decision to use "greatuncle" on page 453 of the ms.
    - Bert Krantz to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, March 8, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      Has received Suttree ms. and outlines process for making corrections and getting them to McCarthy for review.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS. 1 page, plus copy-edited pages, March 21, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Sending queries. Annotated photocopy pages are enclosed
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, March 23, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Discusses previous copy edit questions; asks what dictionary McCarthy uses.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, plus copy-edited pages, April 4, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Sending queries. Annotated photocopy pages are enclosed.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, April 12, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Discusses capitalization of "God/god."
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, April 20, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Sending queries for McCarthy's review.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, April 21, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Discusses copy edit questions.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, May 8, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Has finished first reading; sending queries.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, May 9, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Asking how strongly McCarthy feels about meeting a February publishing date.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, plus copy-edited pages, May 11, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Is on the second "go-round." Annotated photocopy pages are enclosed.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page plus envelope, May 12, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Regarding a previous query about capitalization of "Indian."
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, plus copy-edited pages, May 26, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, plus envelope, May 22, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Discusses reading the proofs.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, plus envelope, June 8, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Going on vacation; galleys will be in when she returns. Asks if McCarthy could get to a phone and call collect to collate.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. Postcard, June 25, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Galleys will be in July 10.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. ALS, 1 page, July 10, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Sending the galleys. Asks to have them back by August 9.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, plus envelope, July 12, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Moving offices and phone number is changing.
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, plus 4 photocopy pages and envelope, August 17, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Galleys received. Sends questions about some of McCarthy's changes.
    - [Bertha Krantz] to McCarthy. ALS, 1 page, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Asks McCarthy's preference for accent marks, capitalization.
  - Notes, undated
    - Spiral notebook, 3" x 5" with 28 holograph pages, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Checklists, 2 pages, undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - "Left from Suttree", undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
      Folder with 113 pages, typescript, holograph, and photocopy. Plus the booklet, "Chess McCartney, 'The Goat Man.' Presidential Handbook," with inserted postcard and pages from a short fiction anthology printing of Wilbur Daniel Steele's "How Beautiful With Shoes."
    - "All Suttree Notes." Envelope with 70 photocopy pages, irregular pagination, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "Suttree Trans." Folder with McCarthy's answers to translator's queries. Photocopy, 4 pages, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Drafts, undated
    - Typescript with some photocopy pages. Holograph corrections in pencil throughout. 856 pages (876 leaves) housed in two parts, each with its original box, undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered "DF-1" - 425 (435 leaves). Irregular pagination, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
        DF-1-DF 6; 1-11; 11a; 11b; 12-73; 73a; 74; 75a; 75-93; 100; 1c-42c; 143-183; 183a; 184-315; 316a; 316a; 316-321; 321a; 322-325; 325a; 326-357; 357a; 358-383; 383a; 384-406; 407&408; 409-425
      - Box for Part 1 in box 20, folder 1. Niftee Copies, Etc. labeled in blue ink, "Ms in two boxes / Suttree / orig ms w/ corr's by CM / pp 1-425" (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 426-857 (441 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 21, Folder 1)
        426-436; 436b-436c; 437-443; 443a; 444-460; 460a; 461-483; 483a; 484-543; 544/545a; 545-637; 637a; 638-665; [no p. #666]; 667-769; 769a; 770-829; 829-830; 830x; 831-857
      - Box for Part 2 in box 21, folder 1. Niftee Copies, Etc. labeled in blue ink, "Ms in two boxes / Suttree / orig ms w/ corr's by CM / pp 426-857" (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Near-exact photocopy of corrected typescript in box 20, folder 1 and box 21, folder 1 with additional light pencil corrections, notably on pages 101-142. 856 pages (874 leaves) housed in three parts, undated
      - Part 1 of 3 numbered "DF-1" through 279 (283 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 22, Folder 1)
        DF1-DF6; 1-11; 11a; 11b, 12-73; 73a; 74-75; 75a; 76-93; 100; 1-42; 143-183; 183a; 184-215; H-15-H-9; 221-279.
      - Part 2 of 3 numbered 280-601 (333 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 22, Folder 2)
        280-316-316a; 316b; 317-321; 321a; 322-325; 325a; 326-357; 357a; 358-383; 383a; 384-406; 408-436; 436a; 436a-436c; 437-443; 443a; 444-460; 460a; 461-483; 483a; 484-543; 544/545a; 545-601
      - Part 3 of 3 numbered 602-856 [missing p. 857]. (258 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 22, Folder 3)
        602-636; 637a; 637-665; 667-769; 769a; 770-829; 829-830; 830x; 831-856.
    - Typescript. Clean with very few pencil marks. 878 pages (879 leaves) housed in two parts, undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 1-400 (401 leaves). Continuous pagination with the exception of two p. 195s and no p. 196 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Box for Part 1. Green Eagle Typewriter Papers box labeled in blue pen, "Suttree – orig ms Part 1" (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 401-878 (478 leaves). Continuous pagination with a few minor exceptions (Box 24, Folder 1)
        401-736; 737a; 737-742; 743&744; 745-831; 834; 833-878
      - Box for Part 2. Eagle-A Typewriter Papers box labeled "Albert T. Erskine" in black; "McCarthy II" in green, and "Suttree Orig Ms part 2" in blue (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of typescript in box 23, folder 1 and 24, folder 1, but with cover sheet "Untitled Novel." Some page numbers missing, but pages in order. No corrections. 878 pages (879 leaves) housed in two parts, undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 1-400 as original, but with an additional title page (402 leaves) (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Box for Part 1. Grey box with white Candida Donadio & Associated, Inc label "Untitled Novel by Cormac McCarthy, I" typed on label. "Suttree Xerox" in blue pencil on box (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 401-878 as original, but photocopy error has fragments of pages 497 & 498 on one page (477 leaves) (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Box for Part 2. Grey box with white Candida Donadio & Associated, Inc label "Untitled Novel by Cormac McCarthy, II" typed on label. "Suttree Xerox" in blue pencil on box (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy with some typescript pages. Holograph corrections in red pen and in pencil. 878 pages with gaps in numbering (751 leaves) housed in two parts, undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 1-390 [no pages 29-115, 130, 325, and 391-400] (302 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 27, Folder 1)
        [title page]; 1-28; 116-129; 131-324; 326-390
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 401-878 [no pages 595, 642, 677, 697-706, 736-737, 776-790, 827] (449 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 27, Folder 2)
        401-433; 433a; 434-440; 440a; 441-594; 596-641; 643-661; 661a; 662-676; 678-696; 707-735; 738-742; 743&744; 745-775; 791-826; 828-878
    - Photocopy with holograph corrections in red ink. 878 pages with some gaps in numbering (822 leaves) housed in three parts, undated
      - Part 1 of 3 numbered 1-279 (276 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 28, Folder 1)
        1-4; 6-32; 32a; 33-38; 38/39; 39-41; 44-91; 91a; 92-125; 127-129; 131-155; 155a; 156-167; 167a; 168-176; 177-183; 183a; 184-189; 193-201; 203-279
      - Part 2 of 3 numbered 280-600 (303 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 28, Folder 2)
        280-319; 326-330; 330a; 331; 332a; 332-340; 345-364; 364a; 365-367; 367a; 368-390; 401-409; 412-425; 427-428; 431-441; 441a-441d; 442-495; 495a; 496-510; 510a; 511-529; 529a; 530; 530a; 531-580; 582-586; 588-592; 596-600
      - Part 3 of 3 numbered 601-878 (243 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 28, Folder 3)
        601-605; 605a; 606-636; 639-641; 644-660; 661a; 661-676; 678-696; 707-726; 728-735; 740-742; 743&744; 745-764; 764a; 765-775; 791-793; 793a; 794-805; 805a; 806-821; 823-825; 828-854; 854a; 855-873; 876-878
    - Photocopy draft with "new" photocopy pages. [Original typescript pages are in the setting copy.] No holograph corrections. 878 pages with some gaps in numbering (821 leaves) housed in 3 parts, undated
      - Part 1 of 3 numbered 1-279, with front matter (282 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 28, Folder 4)
        [ad card]; [half title]; [title page]; [blank]; [second half title]; 1-4; 6-32-32a; 33-38; 38a; 39-41; 44-91; 91a; 92-125; 127-129; 131; 132-155; 155a; 156-167; 167a; 168-176; 176a; 177-183; 183a; 184-189; 193-201; 204-279
      - Part 2 of 3 numbered 280-600 (298 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 29, Folder 1)
        280-319; 326-330; 330a; 331-332; 332a; 333-340; 345-364; 364a; 365-367; 367a; 368-390; 401-409; 412-425; 427-428; 431-441; 441a-441d; 442-495; 495a; 496-510; 510a; 511-529; 529a; 530; 530a; 531-580; 582-586; 588-592; 596-600
      - Part 3 of 3 numbered 601-878 (241 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 29, Folder 2)
        601-605; 605a; 606-636; 639-641; 644-661; 661a; 662-676; 678-696; 707-726; 728-735; 740-742; 743&744; 745-764; 764a; 765-766; 768-775; 791; 793a; 794-805; 805a; 806-821; 823-824; 827-828; 829-842; 844-845; 845-854; 854a; 855-873; 874/876; 877-878
  - Fragments, undated
    - Photocopy fragments of early corrected typescript pages. Some variations from the completed typescript. No holograph corrections. Arranged in lettered sections. 342 leaves, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - "X[erox] of early pages (misc.); no holograph corrections. 71 leaves, plus envelope, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - "Sut - early ms xerox" numbered 42-94. No holograph corrections. (55 leaves), undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - "Suttree X[e]rox pp 230-424." [no p. 230-231]. No holograph corrections. (118 leaves), undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - "Sut - early ms xerox" numbered P1-P83 [669-751]. Includes folder labeled "P", undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Photocopy fragments numbered 333-443. Includes folder labeled "Terrell Co." No holograph corrections, (111 leaves plus folder), undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Proofs, undated
    - Setting copy. Mostly photocopy corrected typescript pages with an additional few dozen typescript leaves (blue) interleaved throughout; holograph corrections in pencil by McCarthy and in red by Erskine. Numbered 1-878 (869 leaves). Irregular pagination, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
      [ad card]; [half title]; [title page]; [copyright page]; acknowledgements]; [second half title]; 1-4; 6-32; 32a; 39-41; 44-91; 91a; 92-125; 127-129; 131; 132-155; 155a; 156-167; 167a; 168-176; 176a; 177-183; 183a; 184-189; 193-201; 203-319; 326-330; 330a; 331-332; 332a; 333-340; 345-364; 364a; 365-367; 367a; 368-390; 401-409; 412-425; 427-428; 431-441; 441a-441d; 442-495; 495a; 496-510; 510a; 511-529; 529a; 530; 530a; 531-580; 582-586; 588-592; 596-605; 605a; 606-636; 639-641; 644-661; 661a; 662-676; 678-696; 707-766; 728-735; 740-742; 744-764; 764a; 765-775; 791-793; 793a; 794-805; 805a; 806-821; 823-826; 828-854; 854a; 855-873; 876-878
    - Envelope for setting copy labeled in marker "Albert Erskine 12-1 / Dead Matter: McCarthy / Suttree / Setting Copy." Also included is a piece of cardboard with page references in red and blue ink and in pencil (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Box for setting copy. Cream and gray (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Vellum page proofs with setting notations, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of page proofs with minor holograph corrections, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of page proofs stamped "Master Set First Pass." Includes manila envelope labeled "Albert Erskine 12-1 / Dead matter: McCarthy, Suttree / 1st pass", undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of page proofs stamped "Master Set Second Pass." Includes manila envelope labeled "Albert Erskine 12-1 / Dead matter: McCarthy, Suttree / 2nd pass", undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Page proofs in sections. Printers marks in red and in pencil. Includes envelope labeled "Albert Erskine 12-1 / Dead matter, McCarthy, Suttree / repro and blues", undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
- Blood Meridian, 1980-1987, undated
  Correspondence, notes, drafts, fragments, and proofs relating to McCarthy's 1985 novel, Blood Meridian. In working drafts and notes, McCarthy referred to this as his "Western."
  - Correspondence, 1980-1985, undated
    - Folder cover marked "This folder has only editorial notes for Blood Meridian…, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - McCarthy to Albert Erskine. Photocopy, 1 page, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
      "Here are the corrections. The pages (31ff) with the red marks on the left margin are all the pages in the ms that have Spanish in them…"
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy, June 4. ANS, 1 page, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Editorial notes, 20 leaves, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Alexandra Halsey to Albert Erskine. TNS, 1 page, June 26, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      Includes 76 leaves of editorial notes and photocopy manuscript pages
    - Bert [Krantz] to McCarthy. ANS, 1 page, June 24, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      Includes 121 pages of "late draft" photocopy manuscript pages.
  - Notes, 1983-1987, undated
    - Holograph notes on language and vocabulary, with page number references. (30 leaves), undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy spiral notebook pages with notes. In folder labeled "OV (West)" and marked "reviewed and abstracted for West – Sept. 83." (34 leaves and 1 folder), 1983 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Typescript vocabulary notes with holograph corrections, December 1983, and photocopy notes. In folder labeled "Western – Final Draft / (Blood Meridian – Left) / [June 87 – sacked / For Pretty Horses." (17 leaves and 1 folder), June, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Typescript pages with holograph corrections, and some holograph pages of notes. In folder marked "Nov 84 All useable material TR'd from these notes. (still some historical stuff here (not usable))." (79 leaves and 1 folder), November, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Photocopy chapter head pages in folder marked "Chapter Heads / Final Notes" and annotated on inside in red ink and pencil. (23 leaves plus folder), undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Drafts, undated
    - Typescript. Heavily corrected in pencil and black ink. Pages 1-169 are absent; includes many additional pages numbered as inserts and additions. So-called "First Draft." (374 leaves). Irregular pagination, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
      "Just before A"; A; [no #]; B; C; 452-453; 453; D; A-1; [no #]; A-2 to A-4; A-4aa; A-4a; 463; A-x; 465?; A-4b; A-7; A-7a; A-8 to A-11; 170-185; 185A to 185C; 22a; 186-192; 26; [no #]; 28; 26a; 193-197; 198a; 199; [2 no#]; 207a; [no #]; 34a-34b; 200-203; 226-235; 75a; 237-242; 79; 243-258; [no #]; 259-263; [no #]; 103; 264-268; [no #]; 269-291; [no #]; 292-299; [no #]; 300-301; 143a; 143; 303; 302; 304-309; 150; 310; [no #]; 311-316; [no #]; 317-318; 158; 158a; [no #] 159; 319; 160; 320-332; 173; 333-339; [no #]; 180; 340; 181; 181a; 341-344; 345a; 345-346; 347a; 347; 188; [no #]; 190; 348-376; 213d/214a; 377-381; 228a; [2 no#]; 228; 382-410; 252; 411-415; 258; 416; [no #]; 417a; 417; 262; 418; [no #]; 419; 419a; 420-422; [holograph notebook page, no #]; 423-424; [no #]; 425-432; 277; 433; 119; 121; 434; LA-1; LA-2; 280a; LA-3; [no #]; EW-2; EW-3; 282; EW-4 to EW-8; 444?; 445?; 446-452; [no #]; 453-545; [no #]; 455-464; 464-465; A-5 and A-6; 466-471; [no #].
    - Typescript, early draft. Heavily corrected in pencil. Includes a map of Sonora and Chihuahua, Mexico, with towns circled in blue ink and a hand drawn map of the US Northwest Territories on the reverse. Also includes a portion of manila folder with holograph notes tracking typing progress. (525 leaves). Irregular pagination, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
      [map]; [title page]; [acknowledgements]; [quotes]; 1-43; 43a; 44-61; 61a; 62-78; 78a; 79-81; 81a; 82-119; 119a; 120-163; 163a; 164-166; 167a; 168-169; 1 (170); 2-25; 25a; 25b; 26-35; 35a; 36-41; 41-44; 44a; 45-48; 49a; 49-56; 56a; 57-63; 63-72; 72a; 73-92; [no #]; 93-114; 114x; 115-117; 117x; 118; [no #]; 119-127; 127a; 128-141; 141a; 142-143; 143a; 143b; 144-148; (149); 149-151; 151a; 152-168; 168a; 169-176; (177); 177-182; 182a; 183-198; (199); 199-203; (204); 204-226; 226a; 227; (228); 228-256; 256a; 257-269; (270); 270-285; (286); 286-303; 303a; 304-305; 305a; 306-314; [folder half].
    - Photocopy incorporating pages from drafts in box 35, folder 9 and box 36, folder 1. Pencil page numbering and corrections on pages 170-185c; otherwise clean. 471 pages (459 leaves) housed in 3 parts, undated
      - Part 1 of 3 numbered 1-112 (107 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 36, Folder 2)
        1-31; 34-89; 91-100; 103-112
      - Part 2 of 3 numbered 113-349. (221 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 36, Folder 3)
        113-115; 118-126; 135-138; 147; [no #]; 139-169; 169a; 170-185; 185a; 185b; 185c; 186-198; 198a; 199-268; 271-273; 275-276; 278-290; [2 no #]; 291-317; [no #]; 322-345; 345a; 346-347; 347a; 348-349.
      - Part 3 of 3 numbered 350-471 (131 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 36, Folder 4)
        350-375; 213d/214a; 376-378; [no #]; 380-389; [no #]; 390-417; 417a; 418-419; 419a; 420-435; EW-1 to EW-2; LA1; LA-3; EW-3 to EW-8; 444?; 445?; 446-453; [no #]; 454-464; 464-465; A-5 and A-6; 466-471.
    - Photocopy draft with red editorial marks throughout. Includes original typescript title page, "A Novel / by Cormac McCarthy," numbered 1-451 with additional pages 319a to 319j (462 leaves) housed in 2 parts, undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 1-236, plus typescript title page (237 leaves) (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 237-451 with additional numbered pages 319a to 319j (225 leaves) (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Printout draft with many typescript pages. Holograph corrections in pencil. Numbered 1-452 (471 leaves). Irregular pagination, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)